## BenVineyard

SR FULLSTACK SOFT WARE ENGINEER

## **HELLO WORLD!**

My name is Ben Lynn Vineyard IV and I am an 40 year old software engineer. I eat, drink, and sleep technology & software. I have been developing software professionally for over 20 years. I am passionate about what I do, confident I can deliver a viable customer product, and skilled enough to make it fly.



#### EDUCATION -

**UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA:** B5 - COMPUTER SCIENCE - 2001 I graduated with a bachelor of science degree in computer science in 2001. I possessed a 3.45 GPA.



## JOB EXPERIENCE—

PRINCIPAL ENGINEER: KASEYA 2018 - Present

Work with a variety of different languages, platforms, & frameworks such as Javascript, Typescript, Classic ASP, ASP.NET, C#, Entity Framework, & SOL Server to maintain flagship VSA product offering.

LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER: STATION CASINOS 2016 - 2018
Led Agile teams developing software on the MEAN (MongoDB,
Express, AngularJS, & Node.js) stack. Migrated legacy solutions off
of the Microsoft stack such as WCF & ASP.NET. Containerized new.
modern solutions using Docker & hosted in AWS & Azure.
Maintained Sitecore based brochure websites via C# solutions.

FOUNDER/CTO: BOTVANA 2013 - 2016

Created search engine optimized, Wordpress-based websites for clients of SEO-For-Lawyers.com. Consulted on a handful of angularJS front-end and nodeJS backend projects.

#### SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER III: IGT 2011 - 2014

I wrote software and provided technical leadership for a team of engineers in both the US & China for IRC and CTA products from IGT's Advantage Suite. The core technologies were C#, WCF, & MSSOL.

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER: COSMOPOLITAN LAS VEGAS 2010 - 2011
Architected & developed a queuing infrastructure for OpenTable vendor system, so that it could integrate from their SQL 2008 based database to both our hotel registration system and master data management system (DataFlux) using C# & MSSQL Service Broker.

#### SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER: AIS 2010 - 2010

Supported and maintained existing ASP.NET & Silverlight web applications with C# managed code-base. Architected & developed a cross-site casino progressive system using WCF 4.0 for message transport, Silverlight 4.0 for the user interface, and SQL 2008 for the data store.



Haywood	Dr	Las	Vegas	NV
1149 11004	υ,,		<b>1</b> CBG2,	

78	702.913.6903	
	, 02.3 13.03 02	i

ben@benvineyard.com

fin	linkedin.com/in/benvineyarc

## **SKILLS-**

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

ASP.NET

nodeJS

C#

angularJS

SQL/NoSQL

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication

Teamwork

Creativity

Leadership

Management

# BenVineyard



### JOB EXPERIENCE-

.NET SOFTWARE DEVELOPER: TECH RESULTS 2009 - 2009
Supported and maintained existing SSIS packages. Designed and authored Silverlight 3.0 web application with WCF back-end.
Supported and maintained existing web application software comprised of ASP.NET front-ends and WCF back-ends.

PROGRAMMER/ANALYST: STATION CASINOS 2005 - 2009
Designed and wrote web and pc applications in VB6, VB.NET, & C#.
Designed and implemented .NET-based service plug-ins in a Service
Oriented Architecture (SOA). Designed and implemented C# web
services and WCF services, exposing customer data on an AS400
IBM mainframe.

**PROGRAMMER:** SILVER STATE SCHOOLS CREDIT UNION 2003 - 2005 Maintained & serviced an ASP/COM based online banking system. Co-Authored and maintained a VB.NET implementation of the aforementioned online banking system, written from the ground up. Co-Authored and maintained a PHP port of the .NET version of the online system.

#### SYSTEM ENGINEER: CAPCO ENT. 2001 - 2003

Designed user interface for Player Rewards kiosk prototype, originally targeted for Mandalay Bay Casino, using Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator. Created the web application for the kiosk prototype using a PHP based frontend and MySQL database backend. Engineered the Debian Linux based environment that the prototype operated in.

#### WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER: ETRONIXX 1998 - 2001

Created basic informational websites utilizing HTML/DHTML/XHTML. Created web applications using classic ASP and PHP.



#### CERTIFIED SCRUM DEVELOPER: SCRUM ALLIANCE 2013

Performed training through Scrum Alliance while employed at IGT and received my Certified Scrum Developer (CSD) certificate in 2013.

#### **CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER: SCRUM ALLIANCE 2013**

Performed training through Scrum Alliance while employed at IGT and received my Certified Scrum Master (CSM) certificate in 2013.